[{"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945f", "question": "How does Jack die in the movie \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "He freezes to death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a0a4cf93664eb10486b9", "question": "What year was the Norwegian non-profit organization, \"Norse Federation\" founded?", "answer": "1907", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f6", "question": "Both Roxette and Sheena Easton had a hit with a song called what?", "answer": "You Got The Look/U Got The Look", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f1876682715b82711ce1", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590721963745b36be73039f8", "question": "What were Frosty the Snowman\u2019s eyes made out of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b53906d333868d34d6e8", "question": "What rocket launched the Apollo program?", "answer": "Saturn rocket", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd69ffe6c0f9723ab15cb31", "question": "Which British monarch is responsible for transforming Buckingham House into a palace?", "answer": "George IV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59bb299bc9bff04efae6d758", "question": "Which kitchen appliance, the first of its kind, was heavily promoted by musician Fred Waring?", "answer": "The blender", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905b", "question": "Once married to Ted Hughes, which American poet committed suicide in 1963?", "answer": "Sylvia Plath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f08", "question": "What author created the character of Dr. Kay Scarpetta?", "answer": "Patricia Cornwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c3e9a0bebfabb9c85d8a977", "question": "What was the birth name of Bing Crosby?", "answer": "Harry Lillis Crosby Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d3", "question": "Isolophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Being alone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b671", "question": "Someone who is called a \"flash in the pan\" could also be described as what?", "answer": "A one-hit wonder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b861", "question": "What sport gives competitors three attempts at the snatch?", "answer": "Weightlifting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b549", "question": "What is \"hotel-Dieu\" in France?", "answer": "A hospital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd69fcd6c0f9723ab15cb2f", "question": "What was the first book sold on Amazon?", "answer": "\"Fluid Concepts And Creative Analogies\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a95", "question": "In ancient Greece, what river did the souls of dead people have to cross?", "answer": "Styx", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cab", "question": "What fictional polo player was first played on screen by swimmer Buster Crabbe?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a0", "question": "How many gallons does a tun barrel typically hold?", "answer": "252", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f53", "question": "Which US actor is the first to star in 8 consecutive number one hit movies?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac7", "question": "Which superhero\u2019s powers could be taken away by the color yellow?", "answer": "Green Lantern", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e86", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Kate in \"Mermaids\"?", "answer": "Christina Ricci", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6e6", "question": "The maxillary bone and the mandible are the upper and lower parts of what?", "answer": "The human jaw", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d2", "question": "What was Murray Langston better known as to the public?", "answer": "The Unknown Comic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7759ceec85e375820b30e", "question": "Where are Zinfandel grapes from?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbeb", "question": "What year saw Jean Paul Gaultier's first individual collection for women?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904a519cf93664eb10486c8", "question": "Following his split with Francine, who does Freddie Femur marry, in the \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic series?", "answer": "Casey Bullocks", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acea", "question": "Which president's wife helped fund the war effort by auctioning wool from sheep grazing on the White House lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f37", "question": "In what movie does Sid Caesar cameo as football coach Calhoun?", "answer": "Grease", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b168", "question": "What year did Big Ben suffer its first major breakdown?", "answer": "1976", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929d", "question": "In \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\", what candy did Willy Wonka create for children who had very little money?", "answer": "The Everlasting Gobstopper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b125", "question": "How were Teddy Roosevelt and Franklin Delano Roosevelt related?", "answer": "Fifth cousins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d2", "question": "What is stored at a depository in Fort Knox?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37f", "question": "Tchaikovsky is considered to have died of which disease?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bc", "question": "What are the three main types of sugar?", "answer": "Glucose, fructose and sucrose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b194", "question": "What year did Napoleon become King of Italy?", "answer": "1805", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3b57c73aa70ea0b70ae8", "question": "Where was the first European settlement in Australia located?", "answer": "Port Jackson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c2", "question": "Which two US states begin with the letter \"V\"?", "answer": "Vermont and Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffcfb4d9dc5ec6cd98a8316", "question": "What painting by Andrew Wyeth depicts a woman lying on the ground?", "answer": "\"Christina's World\"\u00a0-- It depicts a woman lying on the ground in a mostly tawny field, looking up at a gray house on the horizon.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c3", "question": "Which year was Marilyn Monroe born?", "answer": "1926", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b900", "question": "What sport uses clowns to protect the competitors?", "answer": "Rodeo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b5749076251badbeac3", "question": "For what does NAACP stand?", "answer": "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a707", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peach State\"?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81b7dd0de9af39e9d4679", "question": "Who was the first woman to run for President of the U.S.?", "answer": "Victoria Woodhull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d084a1a1c922dd1ac64c2", "question": "In the opera, what kind of factory did Carmen work in?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe775dbeec85e375820b312", "question": "Where are the Baalbek Roman ruins located?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b559e662d71a53650ff8", "question": "In Jane Austen's \"Pride and Prejudice,\" what is Mr. Darcy's first name?", "answer": "Fitzwilliam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cd88bb53d1af658864e9", "question": "What spiced wine is traditionally consumed during the winter months, and especially around Christmas?", "answer": "Mulled wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323204bf195a31e15d738b", "question": "Belmopan is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fb", "question": "What Madonna video won the 1998 MTV Video of the Year Award?", "answer": "Ray of Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc31", "question": "Saffron is derived from the flower of what plant?", "answer": "Crocus sativus, or saffron crocus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba35", "question": "What brand of whiskey is made in Lynchburg, Tennessee?", "answer": "Jack Daniels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5f8", "question": "What US city is nicknamed the \"Crossroads of the West\"?", "answer": "Salt Lake City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a8", "question": "In the movie \"Rebel Without A Cause\", who dies in the chicky race?", "answer": "Buzz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a97820565ad31a57c804", "question": "Where is the \"grassy knoll\" located?", "answer": "Dealey Plaza, Dallas, Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89b", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the Norse god of thunder?", "answer": "Thorium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff8", "question": "Who plays the title character in the 1955 musical \"Daddy Long Legs\"?", "answer": "Fred Astaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2157531a458464a93c45f", "question": "What is the name given to people who make arrows?", "answer": "Fletcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c678", "question": "In which US state can one find Kodiak Bears?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f8b001dd7bf43be5e846", "question": "\"All the news that's fit to print\" is the motto of which newspaper?", "answer": "The New York Times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ecbc08d98002fdd633bf", "question": "Which US state's way of life and culture is described as Cajun?", "answer": "Louisiana's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cff6877e98cb97778a58", "question": "What modern city is situated near Mount Vesuvius?", "answer": "Naples", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3f2", "question": "What is the fear of cosmic phenomenon known as?", "answer": "Kosmikophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b5f5e662d71a53651000", "question": "What was the most popular type of paint during the Renaissance?", "answer": "Oil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba3", "question": "Who wrote the play, \"A Streetcar Named Desire\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89f", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the moon?", "answer": "Selenium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071fa83745b36be73039ec", "question": "What does the abbreviation of Dana's police team, RCAT, stand for in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Revitalized Citizen Arbitration Team", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6d", "question": "What is known as Ireland's \"kissing rock\"?", "answer": "The Blarney Stone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aed", "question": "What is Charlie's last name in Roald Dahl's \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"?", "answer": "Bucket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bb", "question": "What country was the setting for the 2009 movie \"The Hurt Locker\"?", "answer": "Iraq", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc91f660f0007efaba0e57", "question": "In which US state is it illegial to eat an orange in a bathtub?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0b", "question": "How many tiles does a player play to score a bingo in Scrabble?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c1b7877e98cb9777897b", "question": "What Roman building is known as the \"Square Colosseum\"?", "answer": "Palazzo della Civilt\u00e0 Italiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930c", "question": "In the 1997 movie \"Titanic\", how did Jack get tickets to get on board of the Titanic?", "answer": "Through a card game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d07671a1c922dd1ac64b8", "question": "The average adult human has 32 of what?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c75", "question": "What does the Swahili word \"Simba\" mean in English?", "answer": "Lion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0c", "question": "What TV show was made into a movie starring Willie Nelson and Jessica Simpson?", "answer": "The Dukes of Hazzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b875e662d71a53651024", "question": "When was \"Silent Night\" written?", "answer": "1818", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe52b781bf59ab7d2e38103", "question": "What French word does \"collage\" come from?", "answer": "To glue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121bc863c99d48cd169b10", "question": "When someone is breviloquent, they use very few what?", "answer": "Words -- Eloquent people speak beautifully and often at length, whereas breviloquent people like to keep it brief.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a8", "question": "In what US state is Dulles International Airport located?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a6", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba27", "question": "What Cajun dish is a mixture of rice, sausage, chicken, shrimp, oysters, spices and more?", "answer": "Jambalaya", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab1b", "question": "What is the official language of Cuba?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d4", "question": "What does a phonophobe fear?", "answer": "Noise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d3", "question": "What US city gave birth to the Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa04", "question": "The Gorbals is a district of which city?", "answer": "Glasgow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f6b4ff048f679a45aadd", "question": "What did Albert Einstein win the Nobel Prize for in 1921?", "answer": "For his discovery of the law of the photoelectric effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6e", "question": "Who are the three Bronte sisters?", "answer": "Charlotte, Emily and Anne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a6dd20565ad31a57c7e0", "question": "Who was the founding commandant of the Nazi concentration camp Auschwitz?", "answer": "Rudolph H\u00f6ss", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b34", "question": "What famous fashion designer did Rachel begin working for in Season 5 of the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Ralph Lauren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f169ddf7c52aae91cc07d5", "question": "Who played the role of \"Hawkeye\" in the TV show \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Alan Alda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a74d", "question": "Which US state is home to the Catskill Mountains?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3823c73aa70ea0b70acf", "question": "What mode of transportation is Missouri named for?", "answer": "Canoe (An Illinois tribe's phrase for the area's people, \"ouemessourita,\" translates to \u201cwooden canoe people\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa9296ce05a3942286edc", "question": "What musical did the song \"We Need a Little Christmas\" originate from?", "answer": "Mame", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b918", "question": "From what animal do we get fleece?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a26", "question": "Whose \"Small House\" is the subject of the play acted out during \"The King and I\"?", "answer": "Uncle Thomas'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4de9e06d333868d34d718", "question": "The ancient Mayan civilization existed in which modern-day country?", "answer": "Guatemala", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a6f", "question": "The musical \"My Fair Lady\" was based on what classic play?", "answer": "Pygmalion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6992620565ad31a57c742", "question": "According to the Bible, what was Paul's name before it was Paul?", "answer": "Saul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049c77cf93664eb10486a7", "question": "At most, how many Friday the 13th can there be in the same calendar year?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca4a", "question": "What is a particle of light called?", "answer": "A photon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b69b", "question": "What is the edible part of a sea urchin?", "answer": "The gonads", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aada", "question": "In which continent would you find the Amazon river?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906c", "question": "Which famous piece of artwork depicts the \"Battle of Hastings\"?", "answer": "Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe36ce40ada16518afdc03e", "question": "What car company makes the Econoline van", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e8c738e4e5d4832e630b", "question": "For what 1924 crime were Nathan Leopold, Jr. and Richard Loeb arrested?", "answer": "Murder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5bb", "question": "What is the common term for epinephrine?", "answer": "Adrenalin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2b", "question": "Who ferries the dead across the river Acheron in Greek mythology?", "answer": "Charon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa4ab6ce05a3942286eb7", "question": "What is the name of the cat in the film \"Alien\"?", "answer": "Jonsey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea345bff048f679a45aaf7", "question": "What is the name of the biggest part of the human brain?", "answer": "The cerebrum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5921fcfba4edfd43a087adc7", "question": "What number is represented by \"M\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "1,000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72e", "question": "What color tongue does the Chow-Chow dog breed have?", "answer": "Black or blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1f", "question": "From 1964 to 1975, who was the original host of the TV game show \"Jeopardy\"?", "answer": "Art Fleming", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb4fa65ff7d326b622a8b", "question": "In which Shakespearean play would we see the character of Aaron?", "answer": "Titus Andronicus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b571b3b67df192a942e3366", "question": "What is the name of the boy appearing on the Cracker Jack box?", "answer": "Sailor Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e9", "question": "What is the only insect that can turn its head like humans?", "answer": "Praying mantis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dab", "question": "Who satirized the threat of nuclear was in \"The Butter Battle Book\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b30a", "question": "Who uttered the line \"Senator, you are no Jack Kennedy.\"?", "answer": "Lloyd Bentsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a369", "question": "What is the capital of Monaco?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600241ac4be4723ccac2217b", "question": "Which book by Thomas More, published in 1516, depicts an ideal fictional island society?", "answer": "\"Utopia\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd0a9ec223966ae8f88ba", "question": "In the movie \"The Martian\", where were the Mars exterior scenes shot?", "answer": "Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae863427f28483af1e7fdc9", "question": "What was the last imperial dynasty of China?", "answer": "Qing Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de2", "question": "What \"Desperate Housewives\" creator broke into TV as a personal assistant to actress Dixie Carter?", "answer": "Marc Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb0875acf631c2414a13b56", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what are the three names of Daenerys\u2019 dragons?", "answer": "Drogon, Viserion, and Rhaegal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a269", "question": "Turnov, Rusty and Bobo appear in what stage musical?", "answer": "Starlight Express", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ab", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Russia?", "answer": "Elbrus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a892", "question": "What city is home to the Westminster Clock Tower?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ef", "question": "Of the six main cast members on the TV show \u201cFriends\u201d, which was the oldest?", "answer": "Lisa Kudrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a61a", "question": "Which two states share a border with South Carolina?", "answer": "Georgia and North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b9f6364247bf200fb893", "question": "What is a \"Shoal\"?", "answer": "A group of fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd7cae347d002c297e4c4", "question": "What South American cities inhabitants are called \"portenos\"?", "answer": "Buenos Aires", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c6f49076251badbead4", "question": "Who once owned the land on which Arlington National Cemetery is situated?", "answer": "Confederate General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a552c03e1c6f9840ba319d", "question": "Which Asian country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59db75050ab2c8f322317fe3", "question": "On which coast would you find the smallest Canadian province?", "answer": "East coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c5", "question": "What children's book did Forrest Gump keep in his suitcase?", "answer": "Curious George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c93d", "question": "What bird is the smallest living bird?", "answer": "Bee Hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebd", "question": "John Carpenter's \"Assault on Precinct 13\" is an homage to what classic Howard Hawks western?", "answer": "Rio Bravo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1cb", "question": "What primary alcohols go into the standard Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Creme de Menthe and Creme de Cacao", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b35", "question": "What is the name of the winged horse of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Pegasus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48d", "question": "By what name is the Thames known as it passes through Oxford?", "answer": "The Isis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7dc", "question": "What are the four railways in the standard version of Monopoly?", "answer": "The B&O, Pennsylvania, Reading, Short Line", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea337dff048f679a45aaee", "question": "What animal name literally means \"pig-fish\"?", "answer": "Porpoise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397dc", "question": "Who was described by both George Blanchine and Rudolph Nureyev as the worlds greatest dancer?", "answer": "Fred Astaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81e", "question": "What kind of cool star will our Sun become in approximately 5 billion years?", "answer": "A red giant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d18", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Ciccone?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f3", "question": "What animal is \"Artemia salina\"?", "answer": "Brine shrimp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3e", "question": "Which element appears tenth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Neon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae73", "question": "What started in 1849 when gold was discovered at Sutter's Mill?", "answer": "The California Gold Rush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad45", "question": "Who was the first US president to take the oath of office using a nickname?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb40365ff7d326b622a83", "question": "What year was Budweiser first introduced?", "answer": "1876", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339846", "question": "What TV family includes Gomez, Morticia, and Pugsley?", "answer": "Addams Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f050cee580c7f8fd1e4b", "question": "Who was Truman Capote's research assistant for his book \"In Cold Blood\"?", "answer": "Harper Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8ad3101dd7bf43be5e777", "question": "Who invented the color wheel?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901a", "question": "Who painted the \"Rockeby Venus\"?", "answer": "Diego Velazquez", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523ec4736d4be723796b53", "question": "What three provinces requested a single Dominion be formed in 1867, thus beginning to shape modern Canada?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and the Province of Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d0342596a59cbdfbd378", "question": "Who said, \"Nature has given us two ears, two eyes, and but one tongue-to the end that we should hear and see more than we speak\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6002415b4be4723ccac22176", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "Thomas Harris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9bb7d364247bf200fb8a4", "question": "Which UK group won the 1981 Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "Bucks Fizz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cabdbb53d1af658864d2", "question": "On what short story was the 1946 film \"It\u2019s a Wonderful Life\" based on?", "answer": "The Greatest Gift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a13620565ad31a57c7a1", "question": "What is the lowest natural point on Earth?", "answer": "The Challenger Deep", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c046", "question": "Which world champion was beaten by a machine called Deep Blue in 1997?\u00a0", "answer": "Gary Kasparov", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912b", "question": "Which famed science fiction author wrote the novelization for the 1966 film, \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cefc199948005ec986edce6", "question": "What powers Iron Man's suit?", "answer": "Arc reactor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff25b0531a458464a93c475", "question": "Shito pepper is a commonly used condiment in which part of the world?", "answer": "West Africa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a0", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the sun?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff1", "question": "Under what name is Thomas Lanier Williams better known?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b530e662d71a53650ff6", "question": "Writing for a newspaper, what did Edgar Allan Poe encourage his readers to do?", "answer": "Send him encoded messages.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa0", "question": "What is the capital of Niger?", "answer": "Niamey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ba", "question": "What is measured in Poise?", "answer": "Viscosity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50f", "question": "What was the nickname of Alcatraz Prison?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d1155b4fea7fe947a22265", "question": "What year did Arthur Hailey publish the novel \"The Moneychangers\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f43", "question": "What future \"Cheers\" star plays Mob boss Tommy Como in \"Raging Bull\"?", "answer": "Nicholas \"Coach\" Colasanto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600243ad4be4723ccac22199", "question": "Which American author wrote the novel \"The Color Purple\"?", "answer": "Alice Walker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd6bf7e83c707845b216d", "question": "Which vintage player is known as the first superstar of the NFL?", "answer": "Red Grange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede4316ce05a3942286dd9", "question": "Parts of the movie \"Lara Croft: Tomb Raider\" were shot in what African country?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8bc", "question": "What's the only country outside of Africa where lions still live in the wild?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b6f6e662d71a53651011", "question": "Moved by a desire to help people, Vincent van Gogh left art to become what?", "answer": "A priest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b24b", "question": "The Bolshevik Revolution is sometimes known by the name of what month in which it began?", "answer": "October", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcef", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Bilbo Baggins\"?", "answer": "Leonard Nimoy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a10d", "question": "In the \"Nightmare On Elm Street\" films, who played the role of Freddy Krueger?", "answer": "Robert Englund", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071f473745b36be73039ea", "question": "What is the name of Dana and Em's father in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Wayne Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b09", "question": "In Greek mythology, what did Medusa have on her head instead of hair?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4a", "question": "In the movie \"The Matrix\", what colored pill does Neo take?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc29", "question": "What year was football player, David Beckham, born?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac78", "question": "Who invented the modern tire?", "answer": "John Boyd Dunlop", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1cdad7bd84c0ea43ad42c", "question": "Which country borders Macedonia to the south?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be4e", "question": "Who popularized the \"turducken\" by offering one to the winner of Thanksgiving Day NFL games?", "answer": "John Madden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb25", "question": "In the book of Genesis, what is said to measure 300 by 50 by 30 cubits?", "answer": "Noah's Ark", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6ab0820565ad31a57c823", "question": "Who was the commander of German U-boats from 1939 to 1943?", "answer": "Admiral Karl Dointz (also spelled Doenitz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394da", "question": "What was Shari Lewis' hand puppet called?", "answer": "Lamb Chop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb3", "question": "Which cuisine gave us kimchi and bulgogi?", "answer": "Korean", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b456", "question": "What year did Abraham Lincoln deliver the Gettysburg Address?", "answer": "1863", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e8d8fe83fe1f2a824be0", "question": "Who was the last king of the Plantagenet line of monarchs?", "answer": "Richard III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede1366ce05a3942286dc3", "question": "In the 2006 movie \"Flicka,\" what type of animal is Flicka?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe4", "question": "What two countries share land borders with Tunisia?", "answer": "Algeria and Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbe696ce05a3942286eef", "question": "Who recorded the song, \"I Heard a Rumour\"?", "answer": "Bananarama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9d", "question": "How did Scarlett and Rhett\u2019s daughter die, in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Fell off a horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f22", "question": "In a symphony orchestra, what instrument is played by the concertmaster?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6eb", "question": "What mineral is known as the softest mineral?", "answer": "Talc", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339967", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what actor is the voice of Comic Book Guy?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a83b90aac110e416708c", "question": "Who said \"He that drinks his cider alone, let him catch his horse alone.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f369fa5fdd6dd25324da", "question": "Which film producer said \"Anyone who goes to a psychiatrist ought to have his head examined\"?", "answer": "Samuel Goldwyn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa55273838c5c8a417f23", "question": "Who discovered the life or death importance of washing hands while studying maternity wards?", "answer": "Ignaz Philipp Semmelweis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e147775dd42e4a67cb8d3ea", "question": "What is the name of Weird Al Yankovic's 1989 feature film?", "answer": "UHF", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339501", "question": "What year was the movie \"Titanic\" released?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76840eec85e375820b29e", "question": "Which U.S. city is referred to as \"The Hub of the Universe\"?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339327", "question": "In the 1975 movie \"Jaws\", what was the name of Quint's boat?", "answer": "The Orca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3de", "question": "When was Crazy Horse born?", "answer": "1842", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffcd51cf6db9ac4808d04", "question": "Which flag becomes the flag of Poland when turned upside down?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8922ec223966ae8f8826", "question": "Who is the artist who sings \"Beauty School Dropout\" in the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "Frankie Avalon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977b", "question": "Where is the film Predator set?", "answer": "South American jungle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0dcd9fcbed638185eaa0d", "question": "The annual \"Christmas Book Flood\" is part of what country\u2019s holiday tradition?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e4", "question": "How many strikes make up a perfect tenpin bowling game?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339170", "question": "What popular Australian pop star sang the words \"All Beauty Must Die\"?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa3", "question": "What TV family had a road manager named Reuben Kincaid?", "answer": "The Partridge Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c515", "question": "What disease is the focus of oncology?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4f", "question": "What LSU Tiger was drafted by the Orlando Magic in 1992?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60137186138175489539638b", "question": "Who served as butler to the von Trapp family in \"The Sound of Music\"?", "answer": "Franz -- He spent several years as a loyal butler in the service of the Von Trapp family before he betrayed them to the Nazis.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b812", "question": "What is the nickname of Alcatraz Prison?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d6902b42d4a3561a9f05", "question": "What 2010 horror novel by Jeff Strand was nominated for a Bram Stoker Award?", "answer": "Dweller", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ab", "question": "Which country does paella come from?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bb6ad96d05b23b28164e", "question": "In addition to the main Passover, there is also a second one called the Second Passover. When is the Second Passover celebrated?", "answer": "The Second Paassover (also called \"Pesach Sheni\") is observed on the 14th day of the Hebrew Calendar month of Iyar.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b87961d8c1817608d53e9", "question": "Which U.S. monument has a smaller replica hidden in a nearby manhole?", "answer": "Washington Monument  (\"Bench Mark A,\u201d a 12-foot replica of the monument, is a Geodetic Control Point used by surveyors.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017370a44491cbd7c5a1783", "question": "Hugin and Munin were raven spirits that accompanied which Nordic figure?", "answer": "The ravens Hugin and Munin (meaning \"thought\" and \"memory\") are said to sit on the shoulders of the Nordic god Odin.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7e54ff048f679a45ac0b", "question": "A BTU refers to what?", "answer": "The amount of energy required to raise one pound of water one degree Fahrenheit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a57220565ad31a57c7cc", "question": "In which ancient culture were turkeys believed to be gods?", "answer": "Maya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d2", "question": "What disease was once nicknamed \"the white plague\"?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16f", "question": "Karakul, Dorset, Urial, and Jacob are types of what?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59412872bab1e6f9796f1b5d", "question": "Who composed \"Symphonie fantastique\"?", "answer": "Hector Berlioz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925d", "question": "What 1981 movie required some 7,000 snakes?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf9", "question": "The movie \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\" was based on a novel by what popular author?", "answer": "Truman Capote", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ea", "question": "What are the two most common coffee bean types?", "answer": "Arabica and Robusta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c987877e98cb977789f5", "question": "Which Pennsylvania town is the birthplace of \"Rolling Rock Beer\"?", "answer": "Latrobe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd9ee7e83c707845b217f", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" what did Andy write in the Bible for warden Norton to read after he had escaped?", "answer": "Dear Warden, you were right. Salvation lay within.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a2", "question": "Who plays Jullia Robert's best friend in the movie \"My Best Friend's Wedding\"?", "answer": "Dermot Mulroney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3f28c73aa70ea0b70afd", "question": "Mount Godwin Austen, located in the Karakoram mountain range, is better known as what?", "answer": "K2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e475fe83fe1f2a824bb4", "question": "Which Allied country\u2019s forces arrived in Berlin first?", "answer": "USSR's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b937364247bf200fb889", "question": "Who made the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" popular in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4de7906d333868d34d716", "question": "What was the Great Western Schism?", "answer": "When more than one pope claimed authority over the Roman Catholic church.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a276", "question": "What US city is mentioned in the first line of the Bob Seger song \"Turn the Page\"?", "answer": "Omaha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bd05d7740191c55fd523fb7", "question": "Who created the concept of a meme?", "answer": "Richard Dawkins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69ee020565ad31a57c788", "question": "Who was the first US President to deliver his inaugural address entirely from memory?", "answer": "Franklin Pierce", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c455877e98cb9777899d", "question": "Where is the oldest brewery in North America?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff511c7ff04d658268c92ca", "question": "How did Mary Ludwig Hays earn the nickname \"Molly Pitcher\"?", "answer": "During the Battle of Monmouth, she attended to the Revolutionary soldiers by\u00a0bringing them water, often under heavy fire.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb6", "question": "Chandrika Kumaratunga was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d964408b8581f80b092a5", "question": "How old did Canada turn on July 1, 2017?", "answer": "150 years old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8bb", "question": "What is the more common name for Clavicle?", "answer": "Collarbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac4a", "question": "How did Socrates commit suicide?", "answer": "By drinking poison hemlock", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c351", "question": "Which two scientists first proposed that DNA is structured in a double helix?", "answer": "James D. Watson and Francis Crick", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ef", "question": "Kat Dennings and Beth Behrs play the lead roles in what CBS TV show?", "answer": "Two Broke Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c306", "question": "Which is longer, a python or a boa constrictor?", "answer": "A python", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c2", "question": "Which son of Hypnos was the god of dreams?", "answer": "Morpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca64", "question": "What type of creature is an Orb Weaver?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17f", "question": "Who succeeded Pierre Trudeau as the 16th Prime Minister of Canada?", "answer": "Joe Clark", "category": "history"}]